Guide to the Martin Gardner Papers SC0647
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
- Game files, Series 1
  - Paper Folds (Neale), 5 folder(s)
    - 1xN (Linear Strip) [2 of 2], 1966-1982 (Box 23, Folder 19)
      Kaplan, Saul
      Wells, Mark
      Zbikowski, Mark
    - 3x3 Map, 1967-1971 (Box 23, Folder 20)
      Beelzebub puzzle
    - Rectangles, 1970-1971 (Box 23, Folder 21)
      Articles, MG notes
      Russell, Mike
  - Parabola
    - 1981, August, 1969-1982 (Box 52, Folder 13)
      Artwork from article.
      Untitled paper, by Sam Matlin, on a geometric transformation relating parabolas and triangles, and generalized conics (typescript)
      Various articles on the parabola.
      Matlin, Sam
  - Paradox of the Unexpected Examination, 4 folder(s)
    - 1963, March [1 of 2], 1948-1981 (Box 10, Folder 1)
      Various articles, including most of the ones from Mind, with comments by Gardner
      Quines letters include historyof the problem
      Quine, W.V.
      Meltzer, Bernard
      Schoenberg, Judith
      Mendelson, Elliott
      Norwood, Rick (Prisoner's Card Game)
    - Paradox of the Unexpected Examination [2 of 2], 1979-2000 (Box 10, Folder 2)
      more articles
      Chow, Timothy
    - Roy Sorensen, 1986-1991 (Box 10, Folder 3)
    - Letters on Paradox of Unexpected Hanging, 1963-1984 (Box 10, Folder 4)
      Many letters!
  - Parity
    - 1963, December, 1959=1964 (Box 11, Folder 22)
      "Informal deduction in algebra: properties of odd and even numbers", by Commission on Mathematics of the College Entrance Examination Board", pamphlet, 1959
      Seiner, John
      Singleton, C.R.J.
  - Parodies
    - Parodies, 1959-1977 (Box 1, Folder 2)
      Parodies:
      New Yorker, 1965
      New Yorker, 1976
      National Lampoon, 1977
      Gardner's proposal for Humanistic science magazine
  - Pascal Triangle, 9 folder(s)
    - 1966, December [1 of 2] (Box 17, Folder 19)
    - Pascal Triangle [2 of 2], undated (Box 17, Folder 20)
      "Chromatics, as Applied to Mathematics Studies with Pascal's Triangle", by Prof. Siegfried Rosch, 1964, in
      Palette 15 (Internal house magazine of SANDOZ, Ltd.
      "The Incredible Pascal Triangle", by Margaret J. Kenney, Booklet II, Modivated Math Project Activity, Boston College Math. Inst., 1976
      HexStat, from Science Materials Center (rolling beads in a hexagonal layout), with teachers manual [in separate envelop, filed elsewhere.)
    - Misc. Properties & Puzzles, 1966-1975 (Box 18, Folder 1)
      Many articles
      Hoggatt, Verner, Jr.
      Braun, William
    - Pascal Triangle & Probability, 1963-1968 (Box 18, Folder 2)
      (Ruchlis on HexStat, see Box 17, folder 20 [2 of 2] for model
      Ulrich, James
      Ruchlis, Hy
      Morgan, James
    - Generalized to Trinomials, etc, 1960-1967 (Box 18, Folder 3)
      articles & analysis
      Stuermann, Walter
      Tangen, John
    - Fibanacci Numbers, 1966-1972 (Box 18, Folder 4)
    - Patterns of Primes, Multiples of n, etc. [1 of 2], 1966-1971 (Box 18, Folder 5)
      "The Increase of Error Probability When Using P.C.M. Repeaters with Code Converters", by L.E. Legers, Philips research Labs Technical Note 155/66
      "Patterns and Algorithms", by Jerome Rothstein, CIS Research Center Tech. Report, 1971
      Kirka, Richard
      Legers, L.E.
    - Patterns of Primes, Multiples of n, etc. [2 of 2], 1965-1977 (Box 18, Folder 6)
      German articles by Sigfried Rusch (English of one is in Box 17/20 [ 2 of 2])
      "Exploring the Pascal Triangle", by class of The Hyde School, 1975
    - Apex, & Related Material, 1966-1982 (Box 18, Folder 7)
      Wevers, J.H.
      Bonello, Antonio
  - Pathological Curves, 3 folder(s)
    - 1976, December (Box 37, Folder 16)
      Fragments of article, marked for book.
      Shanks, Merrill
    - Gosper's Flowsnake Curve, 1975-1977 (Box 37, Folder 17)
      Many diagrams from Gosper
      Fry, Alan
    - Gosper's Comment on Chapter, 1977-1988 (Box 37, Folder 18)
      More diagrams (from Gosper), many with comments.
  - Pedersen's Strip Solids, 4 folder(s)
    - 1971, September (Box 24, Folder 2)
      Pargeter, A.R.
    - "Sphericity" of Platonic Solids, 1971 (Box 24, Folder 3)
      Dewar, Robert
    - From Mrs. P[edersen], undated (Box 24, Folder 4)
      Jean Pedersen correspondence
      "A New Look at the Platonic Solids", by Jean Pedersen (typescript)
      Various strips for models
    - Gurule's Work, 1971-1985 (Box 24, Folder 5)
      Ben Gurule
      Pictures of his braided polyhedra.
      Patent clames and counterclaims
      Gurule, Ben
  - Pennies, 8 folder(s)
    - 1966, February (Box 15, Folder 19)
      Article, includes triagnular solitaire
    - Rolling Coins, 1965-1993 (Box 15, Folder 20)
    - Isometric Solitaire, 1966-1967 (Box 15, Folder 21)
      (Triangular and rhombic)
      "The Official Triangular Peg Solitaire Handbook", by William Miller, 1979 (typescript)
      analyses by Choros and Harris, and comments on Philpotts analysis (which is in 15/22)
    - Varient Brands, 1966-1986 (Box 15, Folder 22)
      Davis (on Rhomboids) (Harry Davis)
      Philpott analysis (isometric) - triangles and rhombic
      "Think & Jump" (hexagonal)
      Polytaire Problems (Piet Hein)
    - The 10-Triangle, 1966 (?) (Box 15, Folder 23)
      Martin Gardner notes
    - The 15-Triangle, 1965-1988 (Box 15, Folder 24)
      Solutions, proofs
      "A Problem in Triangular Peg Solitaire", by B.L. Schwartz (typescript), 2 versions
      Thomas, R.E.
    - 9 Moves for 15-Trianglular with 5-move sweep, 1966 (Box 15, Folder 25)
    - 21-triangle & 28-triangle & 36-triangle, 1966 (Box 15, Folder 26)
      Various minimum solutions (with some proofs)
      Philpott's comments on Charosh comments
  - Penrose Tiles, 25 folder(s)
    - 1977, January [ 1of 3], 1975-1997 (Box 38, Folder 1)
      Partial article.
      Some slides of paintings by Richard Kurman
      Photo of rug by Tony Banford
      "Quasicrystallography: Some Interesting New Patterns", by P.A.B. Pleasants (photocopy of typescript)
      Shephard, Geoffrey
    - Penrose Tiles [2 of 3], 1988-1997 (Box 38, Folder 2)
      Penrose corrections to original article.
      "Penrose Tilings", by Tami Martin & Art Johnson, ~1992 (typescript)
      Sample of Penrose toilet paper.
      "Termeszet Vilaga" (magazine), Sept. 1997 (includes article by MG)
      Martin, Tami
      Osborn, John
    - Penrose Tiles [3 of 3], undated (Box 38, Folder 3)
      "Termeszet Vilaga" (magazine) Augusst, 1997 (includes article by MG)
      Several articles on Penrose tilings.
    - Quasi-Crystals [1 of 3], 1985-1999 (Box 38, Folder 4)
      Lots of articles, clippings, etc, on quasi-crystals.
      Rhombic Hexahedron modules, pictures, patent (of C. Perry), instructions -- from Helmut Bergman
      Bergman, Helmut
    - Quasi-Crystals [2 of 3], 1989-1997 (Box 38, Folder 5)
      More articles.
      Heldring, Otto
    - Quasi-Crystals [3 of 3], 1986-1999 (Box 38, Folder 6)
    - Conway's Non-Periodic 3D Tile (Convex), 1993 (Box 38, Folder 7)
      The model framework on file-folder paper (to be cut out), and a short article from Focus.
    - Nori's Algorithm, 1987 (Box 38, Folder 8)
      "A Very Simple Algorithm That Generates an Infinite Sequence of Aperiodic Patterns", by Marco Ronchetti and Franco Nori ["Just a Preliminary and Incomplete Draft"] (typescript), along with around 30 examples.
      Nori, Franco
    - de Bruijn Material [1 of 2], 1980-1982 (Box 38, Folder 9)
      2 papers (typescript) by de Bruijn
      De Bruijn, N.G.
    - de Bruijn Material [2 of 2], undated (Box 38, Folder 10)
      More de Bruijn papers.
      Bibliography of de Bruijn papers on Penrose patterns.
    - Ammann's Tiles, 1969-1996 (Box 38, Folder 11)
      Many hand-drawn aperiodic examples.
      Some proofs, in letters
    - Originals of duplicated pages, undated (Box 38, Folder 12)
      From folder 38/11
    - Conway Material, 1975-1980 (Box 38, Folder 13)
      Notes on Conway lecture on the tiles, Bell Labs, 1980.
      Lots of notes (and corrections) about the tiles.
      Slides from a Conway lecture
      Guy, Richard (for J.H.C.)
    - Originals of duplicated pages, undated (Box 38, Folder 14)
      From folder 38/13
    - Forcing Theory, 1977 (Box 38, Folder 15)
      MG report to Penrose on what Conway has been doing with Penrose tiles, partly on how Ammann bars "force" other infinite sets.
    - Non-Periodic Tiling, 1970-1981 (Box 38, Folder 16)
      Spiral and other non-periodic (but not aperiodic) tilings.
      Kershner, R.
      Wallace, John
    - 3-Space Non-Periodic Tilings, 1976-1989 (Box 38, Folder 17)
    - Ellen Perstein, 1999-2001 (Box 38, Folder 18)
      "Tilings with Penrose Rhomb Clusters", by Ellen Perstein (color computer output), plus discussion.
      Perstein, Ellen
    - Wnag Dominoes, 1965-1977 (Box 39, Folder 1)
      Articles & letters on Wang tiles.
      "Computers, Games, and Logic", by Hao Wang (typescript)
      Hart, Tim
      Robinson, Raphael
    - Robinson - on th ePenrose Tiles, 1975-1976 (Box 39, Folder 2)
      Articles (& letters) on Penrose tiles
      "Comments on the Penrose Tiles - September 1975", by Raphael M. Robinson (typescript)
    - Eric Rogener, undated (Box 39, Folder 3)
      Some kite and dart tilings
    - Harborth & P. Hein, 1976 (Box 39, Folder 4)
      Harborth, Heiko
    - Pauling's Criticisms, undated (Box 39, Folder 5)
      About quasicrystals
    - Theo Bense (New Zealand), 1991-1992 (Box 39, Folder 6)
      Various 3-D models based on Penrose tiling, with pictures & description. Also article in Dutch.
      Bense, Theo
    - Miyazaki, 1978 (Box 39, Folder 7)
      "On Some Periodical and Non-Periodical Honeycombs", by Koji Miyazaki, 1977 (booklet, with many laid-in photos. Also mentions Golden Polytopes and Golden Isozonohedra.)
      Miyazaki, Koji
  - Pentomino Games, 3 folder(s)
    - 1965, October, 1965-1994 (Box 15, Folder 5)
      "The Game of Pentominoes: A First Player Win", by Hilarie K. Orman, 1994 (typescript)
    - De Bono's L-Game, 1974-1984 (Box 15, Folder 6)
      Dewdney, A.K.
      Penszko, Marek
    - Rectification Problem (form rectangles), 1964-1989 (Box 15, Folder 7)
      "Rectifiable Polyominoes", by "Group Four", VCP (reproduction)
      "Polyominoes Which Tile Rectangles", by Solomon Golomb (typescript)
      Spira, Robert
  - Pentominoes, 2 folder(s)
    - 1960, November, 1960-1962 (Box 6, Folder 18)
    - Domino's and Fault-Free Rectangles, 1960-1976 (Box 6, Folder 19)
  - Perfect No's
    - 1968, March (Box 20, Folder 1)
      Just article.
      Other folders: Weird numbers, number problems
  - Phi
    - 1959, August (Box 5, Folder 3)
      (just the article)
  - Pi
    - 1960, July, 1960-1993 (Box 6, Folder 7)
      "The Number Pi", by Edmund Kelly
  - Pierce, 5 folder(s)
    - 1978, July (Box 45, Folder 1)
      Charles Sanders Pierce
      Eisele, Carolyn
      Jones, Charles
    - Pierce's 1, 2, & 3rd ness, 1978 (Box 45, Folder 2)
      Hartshorne, Charles
      Fisch, Max
    - Burks, on Pierce, 1976 (Box 45, Folder 3)
      Papers (typescript) by Arthur Burks
      Burks, Arthur
    - Chas. Pierce - Misc. Papers on, undated (Box 45, Folder 4)
    - Pierce's Card Trick, 1965-1985 (Box 45, Folder 5)
      Anderson, Sabra
      Eisemann, Kurt
  - Pigeon-Hole Principle
    - 1980, August (Box 51, Folder 10)
      Incomplete article (article written by Ross Honsberger)
      Dewdney SA article on Honsberger
      Rebman, Ken
  - Platonic Solids
    - 1958, December, 1958-1962 (Box 4, Folder 13)
      Resistance Cube Puzzle
      Wetter, Arthur
      Parkenson, R.A.
      Eklund, Karl
  - Pocket Calculator
    - 1976, July, 1970-1992 (Box 37, Folder 2)
      DeLong, Howard
      McPhee, Mary Jo
      Jud, Wallace
  - Point-Set Coverings of Spheres, 2 folder(s)
    - Point-Set Coverings of Spheres (Conway, Simmons) [2 of 2], 1973 (Box 27, Folder 10)
      Lots of correspondence & articles from/with Simmons
    - 1973, September [1 of 2], 1973-1985 (Box 27, Folder 9)
      No article (1 page photocopy)
      Croft, H.
      Angstrom, Knut
      Alma, G.G.P.
  - Polycubes (& Soma II)
    - 1972, September, undated (Box 25, Folder 16)
      Just article (incomplete)
      (includes Slither)
  - Polyominoes
    - 1957, December (Box 2, Folder 17)
      More about complex dominoes (December, 1957)
      References a separate box of letters
  - Primes, 7 folder(s)
    - 1964, March (Box 12, Folder 13)
      Column
    - Ulam's Spiral, 1964-1966, 2000 (Box 12, Folder 14)
      "A Visual Display of Some Properties of the Distribution of Primes", by M.L.Stein, S.M. Ulam, M.B.Wells (typescript of article)
      Ducker, W.L.
      Jones, Florence
      Amick, Owen
      Clark, Arthur C.
    - Correspondence on the Spiral Pattern [1 of 2], 1964-1966 (Box 12, Folder 15)
      Are the pictures wrong?
      Hexagonal plot
      Rows of squares
      "The Structure of the Prive Number", by Wang Chia-chu (photocopy of typescript)
      Richter, Charles
      Nelson, W.L.
      Stuart, James
      Baumgant, Bruce
      Eisenberg, Frank
      Phelan, Stephen
    - Correspondence on the Spiral Pattern [2 of 2], 1985-1987 (Box 12, Folder 16)
      3 Reports from Naval Surface Weapons Center, by R. S. Sery:
      "A New Method for Finding Prime-Rich Equations of the Type I=x^2-x+c" (1986)
      "Prime-Rich Row Equations of the "Special" Array" (1987)
      "Relationships Between Prime-Rich Euler Type Equations and a Triangular Array of the Odd Integers" (1985)
    - Triangular Grids [1 of 2], 1932-1964 (Box 12, Folder 17)
      "A Triangular Arrangement of Numbers Leading to the Graphical Determination of Euler Sequences", by L.M.Klauber (1932) (Thermofax of typescript)
      "Never Prime" Seive, & "Prime Likely" Sieve (triangular), by Klauber
      Klauber, L.
    - Triangular Grids [2 of 2], 1963-1964 (Box 12, Folder 18)
      Brooks, Rodney
    - Hexagonal Grids`, 1964-1987 (Box 12, Folder 19)
  - Prismatic Rings, 3 folder(s)
    - 1978, August, 1976-1990 (Box 45, Folder 6)
      Slides from Ikuo Sakurai, photos from Quimby
      McAdams, H.T.
      Sequin, Carlo
      Peavey, L.H.
      Evans, Pierce
      Draper, S.W.
      Ferguson, Helaman
    - Early Letters on, 1964-1978 (Box 45, Folder 7)
    - Scott Kim on, 1976-1978 (Box 45, Folder 8)
  - Probability II, 4 folder(s)
    - 1959, October, 1959, 1991 (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - Broken Stick, 1959-1990 (Box 5, Folder 6)
      analysis of "at random"
      Kling, Frederick, John Ross, Norman Cliff
      Redheffer, Ray
      James, Robert
      Lynch, Gerald
      Bach, G. and R. Sharp
      Knalf, David
      Geschwind, Norman
    - Random Chord (Bertrand's Problem), 1939-2002 (Box 5, Folder 7)
      Goldman, Thomas
      Lydiard, J.M.
      Jaray, R.J.
      Bauer, Richard
      MacQueen, J.T.
    - Paradox of 2nd Child, 1959-1992 (Box 5, Folder 8)
      McVey, Joseph
      Kemeny, John
      Rosenstock, Herbert
      Heironimus, J.P.
      Baron, Julius
      Collier, J.H.
      Lincoln, Alexander
      Olson, Roger
  - Probability Paradoxes, 8 folder(s)
    - 1957, April (Box 1, Folder 13)
      "Paradoxes dealing with birthdays, playing cards, coins, crows and red-haired typists"
    - Hempel's Paradox, 1968 (Box 1, Folder 14)
      MG card model of Hempel's paradox (undated)
    - Letters on Hempel's Paradox, 1957-1988 (Box 1, Folder 15)
      Arabadjis, Gus
      Smith, Preston
      MacIver, Donald
      Hobson, Paul
      Alchian, Armen
      Barnhart, E. Paul
      Isen, Werner
      Geppert, Donovan
      "Steve"
      Smith, Dan
      Colman, Morris
      Michie, Donald
      Porte, Jean
    - Papers and references on Hempel's Paradox [1 of 2], 1946-1985 (Box 1, Folder 16)
      "The Priggish Principles", I.F. Good
      Hacking, Ian
    - Papers and references on Hempel's Paradox [2 of 2], 1957-1997 (Box 1, Folder 17)
      Swinburne, Richard
      Stove, David
      Shotwell, David
    - 1970, December, 1969-1971 (Box 23, Folder 10)
      Various discussions of paradoxes
    - Non-Transitive Dice [1 of 2], 1970-2000 (Box 23, Folder 11)
      "Non-Transitive Dominance Relations Among Dreidels", by R. Tenney & Caxton Easten (typescript)
      Rosen, Joe
      Efron, Bradley
      Thorp, Edward
    - Non-Transitive Dice [2 of 2], 1975 (Box 23, Folder 12)
      "Latest Last Entry Time and Proper Strategic Choice from Among a Certain Set of Options having Non-Transitive Advantages", by W.W. Fukenbusch, Dept. of Math, Michigan Tech. U., 1974 (booklet)
  - Problems, 10 folder(s)
    - 1972, April, 1967-1972 (Box 25, Folder 1)
    - Dudney's Digit Problem, 1972 (Box 25, Folder 2)
      Many computer solutions of problem #7
    - Variants - using Digits, 1972 (Box 25, Folder 3)
      Of problem #7, multiplying numbers using the 9 digits, different bases, addition, etc.
      Crocker, Guy
    - 10-Digit Variant, 1972 (Box 25, Folder 4)
      Variants of #7, but multipying using 10 digits (0-9)
    - Simmon's Band and Cord Variant, etc, 1972 (Box 25, Folder 5)
      Variants of #1, folding strip with ends attached (also folding cards.)
    - Frieze Patterns (Coxeter & Conway), 1971-1972 (Box 25, Folder 6)
      Various reprints & preprints of articles on Frieze patterns.
      Conway notes (June, 1972) on Frieze patterns, also "unimpartial hackenbush"
      "The Geometry of Frieze Patterns", by D. Broline & D.W. Crowe (typescript)
    - 1979, December, 1977-1996 (Box 49, Folder 18)
      Corrections to several problems.
      Boas, R.P.h
      Penny, Walter
    - The "Impossible" Number Problem [1 of 2], 1979 (Box 49, Folder 19)
      Lots of solution procedures, reports on statement error (sum cannot be limited to 20), etc.
      Dijkstra, Edsger
      Hull, Thomas
      McCarthy, Don
    - The "Impossible" Number Problem [2 of 2], 1979-1993 (Box 49, Folder 20)
      "The Impossible Problem", by Lee Sallows (typescript)
      Agin, Gerald
      Lew, John
      Sallows, Lee
    - Taylor's Linked Toruses, 1979-1980 (Box 49, Folder 21)
      Various alternative diagrams of solutions (and variations)
      Photos of a solution in clay & brass ring (by Fieux).
      Francis, George
  - Problems - 11, 9 folder(s)
    - 1963, November (Box 11, Folder 13)
      Lohr, Lenox
    - Bracing a Square, 1963 (Box 11, Folder 14)
    - 23-Rods, 1963 (Box 11, Folder 15)
      Andersen, Eric
    - Rigidifying Higher Polygons, 1999 (Box 11, Folder 16)
      Bracing a pentagon & hinged dissection
    - 3-D Mazes, 1962-1964 (Box 11, Folder 17)
    - Word Squares, 1963-1965 (Box 11, Folder 18)
    - Clock Problem, 1963-1964 (Box 11, Folder 19)
    - Schuh's Problem, 1963 (Box 11, Folder 20)
    - Proofs of Max. Move Chess Problem, 1963 (Box 11, Folder 21)
  - Problems - 13, 8 folder(s)
    - 1965, November, 1964-1965 (Box 15, Folder 8)
      Word and number problems
      Source of #6
      Comment on key & ring
    - Sam Loyd's toothpick Problem, 1965 (Box 15, Folder 9)
      Various general solutions and proofs
      Brown, J.C.
      Ungar, Andrew
      Beach, Breat
      Allen, D.J.
      Shepherd, W.A.
      Dickson, John
      Brewster, George
      Bienenfeld, David
    - Rectangle-Free Squares, 1965-1966 (Box 15, Folder 10)
      also Formulas for rectangle-free problem on squares
      Knowlton, William
    - Lady in Lake, 1965-1967 (Box 15, Folder 11)
      Max, Nelson
      Perry, R.L.
    - Glass-Test Goof, 1964-1965 (Box 15, Folder 12)
      Hall, David
    - The Anagram Dictionary, 1964-1966 (Box 15, Folder 13)
      Temperley, Nicholas
    - Barr's Sets of Cocircular points, 1965 (Box 15, Folder 14)
    - Rolling Cube Tours, 1964-1997 (Box 15, Folder 15)
      Gough describes games: Relate, Egyptian Game
      Gough, John
  - Problems with Game Material, 6 folder(s)
    - 1978, February, 1972-1978 (Box 43, Folder 10)
    - Sicherman Dice, 1977-1979 (Box 43, Folder 11)
      Gallian, Joseph
      Broline, Duane
      Sicherman, George
    - The Complex Polytope, 1977-1992 (Box 43, Folder 12)
      Karl Scherer's proof of square problem: 8 is minimum no. of equal squares with each vertex shared
      Youngs, Dale
      Scheerer, Karl
      Mycielski, Jan
    - 27 Dice Problem, 1978 (Box 43, Folder 13)
      Some nice analysis
      Jackman, Kenneth
      Lipscomp, Kenneth
      Lopow, Leonard
    - Conway's Checker Jump, 1979, 1997 (Box 43, Folder 14)
      Only 2 articles on problem and variations
    - Kruskal Kount, 1975-1976 (Box 43, Folder 15)
      Various discussions of presentation
      Endfield, Cy
      Lerman, Benjamin
      Hudson, Charles
  - Pythagorean Theorem, 4 folder(s)
    - 1964, October, 1958-1972 (1998) (Box 13, Folder 13)
      Also Pythagorean triangles
      Proofs, generalizations
      Loomis, E.G.
    - Equiareal PP Triangles, 1960 (Box 13, Folder 14)
    - Pythagorean Triples, 1960-1995 (Box 13, Folder 15)
      "The Pythagorean Numbers in Vector Problems", by Leo Lavatelli (typescript)
      Umansky, Harlan
      Rathbun, Randall
    - Matrix' Prediction, 1964 (Box 13, Folder 16)
      (tail end of October article, Pythagorean Theorem)
      Notes on how he (MG) did it, with other possibilities
  - Quicky Problems, 3 folder(s)
    - 1971, July (Box 23, Folder 23)
    - Pentagon Viewing Problem, 1971 (Box 23, Folder 24)
      Lots of claims of falsity
    - The 24 Touching Cubes, 1971 (Box 23, Folder 25)
      Also details of 22 cube solution; also hypercube solutions
      Fischer, Michael
      Fawcett, Kenneth
      Riley, John
      Ogilvy, Stan
  - Ramsey Theory, 15 folder(s)
    - 1977, November, 1977-1989 (Box 42, Folder 6)
    - Ramesy Theory (Refs), 1979-1996 (Box 42, Folder 7)
      Notes by MG
      Various papers, reviews, etc
      Long survey article (typescript) by Stefan Burr, nd (about 1975)
    - Papers by Fan Chung, 1982-1988 (Box 42, Folder 8)
    - R(4,5)=25 (Ann Landers), 1993 (Box 42, Folder 9)
      Ann Landers mention of Ramsey(4,5) being 25, with letter from MG in response
    - Readers - Corrections & New Material, 1977 (Box 42, Folder 10)
      Basin, Lewis
      Lorden, Gary
    - Forced Chromatic Triangles in Graphs (& Blue-empty ones), 1962 (Box 42, Folder 11)
      Jenks, Robert
    - Ramsey No's for Cycles (Polygons), undated (Box 42, Folder 12)
      MG notes and 2 article reprints
    - Graham's Hypercube Problem, undated (Box 42, Folder 13)
      Knuth article on large numbers, but *no Graham!*
    - Multiple Disjoint Triangles, undated (Box 42, Folder 14)
    - Ramsey No's for Stars, undated (Box 42, Folder 15)
      MG notes, 2 articles (by Burr & others)
    - Spoked Wheels, undated (Box 42, Folder 16)
    - R(3,3,...) Problems, 1977 (Box 42, Folder 17)
      MG notes & articles by Folkman
    - Erdos-Graham Problem, 1977 (Box 42, Folder 18)
      MG notes & some articles
    - Euclidean Ramsey Theory, undated (Box 42, Folder 19)
      "Euclidean Ramsey Theorems", I, II, III, by Erdos, Graham et. al. (photocopy)
    - Related Problems (Ramsey Type), 1978 (Box 42, Folder 20)
      Lots of articles
  - Random Numbers, 2 folder(s)
    - 1968, July (Box 20, Folder 7)
      Fink letter on Borges.
      Fink, Federico
    - Random Number Generators, 1968 (Box 20, Folder 8)
  - Random Walks I (Linear)
    - 1969, May, 1968-1983 (Box 21, Folder 11)
      MG notes on betting games with Red/Black cards (with letter from Enn Norak and notes from Persi Diaconis)
      Mackay, Alan
      Norak, Enn
  - Random Walks II (Plane and Space), 4 folder(s)
    - 1969, June (Box 21, Folder 12)
      Einstein knew of Brownian motion: excerpts of translations of Einstein, from Karol Mysels
      Various other non-technical articlas on random walks, from Quandum, the Sciences, American Science, Math Horizens, Sci. Am.
    - 2-Dim. Walks, 1969 (Box 21, Folder 13)
      Notes & articles on Brownian Motion
      MG notes on triangular random walks
      Weiss, Mitchell